this whole competition.
This is the first of the new series of the Diving World Series.
Can Panda Lele or Megan really upset them?
Tonya Couch is capable of some high quality diving.
But it's the 16 year old Alejandro Orozco who will get us underway.
She participates in the 2012 Olympics in the synchronized 10-meter platform.
Now she's going solo, and she'll start us off.
The order of divers, Orozco, Couch, Filion, Pandelera, Benfito, and Luis Picia.
Here's the judges, seven judges.
The best two scores and the worst two scores will be taken out of the reckoning.
The three in the middle multiplied by the degree of difficulty will determine the score for each particular dive.
In the women's event, there are five dives.
Each has been predetermined.
And the degree of difficulty is known in advance.
Coaches getting ready.
There's Pandalela's coach.
So the Guadalajara born at Roscoe for Mexico will get us underway.
Women's 10 meter platform.
7th of 8th events at this diving World Series event in Beijing.
Athletes then have to think of.
Getting the passport stamped and moving on to the United Arab Emirates because Dubai is next week, but firstly focus.
On this.
This will be a forward three and a half somersault in the pike position.
Degree of difficulty three.
Nicely delivered from Alejandro.
Getting the first dive out of the way.
So important you're looking for.
Low 70s mid 70s if you're down.
Diving first to get yourself up and running.
And then Oscar that's nicely executed.
Toes were together, which is always a good indication.
Solid score, solid start of 67.5 for a Roscoe.
This is 24 year old Tonya Couch, hails from Plymouth in the southwest of England, arriving from Great Britain.
It's a backward two and a half somersault with one and a half twists.
Nice clean entry from Tonya.
A 3.2 degree of difficulty to get her.
Five dives up and running.
Again, anything around mid 70s is a solid start.
Chinese divers will be looking for the mid 80s, but anything mid 70s it's.
It's just about right.
Toes nicely pointed entry good.
And a 75.2 score, two eights and a 7.5.
The judges scores the count, multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
First of the two Canadians, this is Rosley and Filion.
Tiny diver.
Bundle of energy.
Forward three and a half somersault.
Nice, confident approach.
And the coaches are happy.
They think she's nailed it.
Going to bronze at the 2012 Summer Olympics in the Synchro event.
Spotting the entry, she's picked up 63 points, which is possibly a little bit less than I think the coaches reckon she deserved.
Three sevens the scores that count.
Instant feedback from all the coaches.
Alright, Malaysia's Pandela Rinong.
Bronze medalist at the 2012 Olympics in this competition.
Forward three and a half somersault in the pike position.
The degree of difficulty, 3.0.
Again, a lovely, clean entry into the water from Pandalela.
She's still only 21 years of age, comes from East Malaysia, Sarawak.
There's much of her training up here in Beijing.
She's picked up a 76.5 opening ground score.
That's a very solid start from Pandalela.
Megan Benfato.
She's up next.
The first of her five dives will be a forward three and a half somersault.
Dive 107B as they call it.
Same as we've just seen from Pandalela.
25 year old who hails from Montreal in Canada.
Again, there's good reaction from her coaches.
She won her qualifying group earlier on this morning.
It is always good for confidence.
Nice tight pike.
Spots the entry.
Toes nice and close together.
73.5 and 8.5 and two eights.
The scores, the counting.
Eight, the lowest any of the seven judges awarded at.
Now then, the favorite, Lu Hsiao.
The dive of choice, the forward three and a half somersault in Pike.
Rapturous applause.
She's rather overshadowed by Chen Ruolin is Lihui Xia.
She won one of these tournaments in last year's World Series event.
She's got off to a cracking start here.
Nice tight pike.
Confident approach.
Straight legs.
Out early into the dive and a perfect entry.
82.5 is the unofficial scoring card.
The official confirmation comes now indeed 82.5 and 9.5 and two nines.
Anything 9.5 is perceived to be excellent.
And that's a first round lead as expected for you.
He's here.
And the leather inong from Malaysia.
Currently in second place, 1.3 points ahead of Britain's Tonya couch.
With Megan Bonifeto a further 1.7.
Down in fourth place.
Good start.
Back to Alejandro Orozco.
She'll start this time with an arm stand.
And then we'll release into a back double somersault.
Really have difficulty 3.2.
Looking for the approach, you're looking for how solid the arm stand is.
Athletic agility and strength required at the top of the dive.
And then you've got to execute.
And I think she's executed a pretty solid dive.
Toes nicely together at the finale.
That's always a good indication.
And a 75.2 for a total of 142.7 is
Good effort by the girl from Guadalajara.
It's on your couch from Great Britain.
Inward three and a half somersault.
3.2 degree of difficulty.
Lovely strong stance on tiptoes.
And a good execution.
She's got a gymnastic background, has Tonya.
Quickly into the pike.
Perhaps didn't just spot her entry into the water perfectly.
It's solid, though.
70.4, two 7.5s and a seven counting.
Overall 145.6.
Coaches are poolside.
Instant feedback from just about every dive.
Filion.
Backward three and a half somersault degree of difficulty her higher so far three point three
26-year-old native of Quebec.
Looks a little bit rushed as she's just trying to get out of the back somersault.
Makes them comfortably.
Toes pointed.
69.3.
Full stretch is the coaching tip.
As Pandelela prepares.
Backwards two and a half somersaults in the pike position.
Currently second after the first round.
That's very nicely delivered.
Good aggressive movement into the pike.
Not early, arched back just a little bit over.
giving a bigger splash than it probably deserved.
It's a 69.68 across the board.
146.1.
So she'll be at the very least in the top three.
What depends on the dive executed by Megan Benfato.
She took a long time to settle in with three and a half somersaults in the tuck position.
She needs 72.6 to leapfrog Pandalela.
She really did take a long time to set herself before getting into that tuck.
Not exactly perpendicular, so Megan has 64 for 137.5.
The danger is she might drop from second to fifth, such as the tightness of competition in this women's final.
This the clear leader from the first round.
An inward three and a half somersault in tuck.
Lovely spring to get just that little bit of extra height.
Tight summer salts.
Nice tight tuck.
Always seems to have so much time and barely a ripple on entry into the pool.
That's a 78.4 for Lu Hsiao.
And top ranked again, an 8.5.
It was a nine, marked by one of the judges as the highest, and a 7.5 chalked off.
So after two rounds.
Lu Xixia leads 14.8 points clear of Pandalela Rinong, who is just 0.5 clear of Tonya Couch.
That's a good battle.
Any one of second to sixth could be in the podium at the end of five rounds.
But good start from Pandalela.
Tonya, very competitive but outstanding from the Chinese athlete Lu Xixia.
We are at the WaterCube, the venue for the Diving World Series 2014, the first competition of the season here in Beijing.
It's the eighth season of the FINA Diving World Series, sponsored this year by NVC Lighting.
Mexican fans everywhere.
Alejandro Rosco.
Great experience for the 16 year old.
A 3.2 degree of difficulty for that inward three and a half somersault.
The youngest ever athlete to represent Mexico at the 2012 Olympics.
That's a very solid dive.
Recognized by the judges, little peek at the scoreboard 72.
37.5, the scores the count from the judges.
Little nod of approval from her coaches on the poolside.
It's Tonya Couch from Plymouth.
Forward three and a half somersault.
Good confidence approach.
Nice spring into the dive.
Just gets that little bit of extra air.
What's the execution like in the air?
The marking is a 67.5.
She doesn't bring nods of approval from Tonya.
I think she thought she was a little bit better than that.
Goes to the coaches.
Filion currently ranked sixth, but a good dive here can really elevate her.
This will be an inward two and a half somersault from Pike.
Spotted that very nicely.
It's a 2.8 degree of difficulty.
So the execution has got to be just about perfect to pick up good points Anything approaching the high 60s 70s is a job very well done She won't be far off that
Nice tight piker, release.
Toes pointed, overshoots the entry.
2.8s and a 7.5.
Then stretch, 198.10 is the total.
With a 65.8 score by the judges.
Now Pandelela from the arm stand.
This will be a back double somersault.
They have to go through each of the disciplines throughout their five dives.
Little push off on the arms, absolutely essential.
It was a good strong arm stand.
And I think she scored highly on that one.
The twist is strong, the toes are pointed and perfectly together.
It's always the last little clue.
That's the important element, the little push just as you're falling.
Nice clean entry on Panda Lela.
is rewarded with a 76.8.
It's approaching the very good category.
Ben Faito was a genuine contender after the first two rounds and slipped away a little bit.
A 3.3 degree of difficulty.
Wasn't the perfect entry.
Back with three and a half somersaults in the tuck.
Did she get out of the tuck in time?
There's plenty of spring into the tuck, but coming out of it, she's
There's a big splash there.
The entry is such an important element.
Just unable to flick the legs forward.
10 meters is a long way up, but as soon as you're in the air, it disappears very quickly.
A 57.8.
Clear leader, Liu Huixia.
This is the arm stand.
Followed by a backwards double somersault.
Lovely.
Great form and great strength on the arm stand.
Perfectly perpendicular.
Then a little push away to give her the time to perform this somersault element in the execution.
And an excellent clean entry.
High marks almost guaranteed for that.
Again, that's the element and she just buys herself
Extra time, almost too much extra time.
Yuhi Xia, three nines count and 86.4.
It's her best dive of the competition.
It's the best dive of the competition so far.
18 dives so far, 12 still to go.
Two each for each of the competitors still.
Pandelela holding on to second place.
In fact, she's strengthened that and Orozco, the young Mexican, has leapfrogs on your couch into the podium positions.
As you can see, healthy attendance for this diving competition.
We do head off around the globe.
And the big screens.
A modern-day curse.
And she knows she's got fans in the audience, does Alejandro.
Now she just needs to focus.
This is the fourth round.
The degree of difficulty selected, 3.2.
The divers are backwards.
Two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists.
Currently ranked third.
Solid dive to keep on the podium.
They can be pretty proud of that effort.
She's put in a very consistent series of dives, which for youngsters is very often one of the difficulties of getting consistency.
Rounds one, two, and three were 67.5, 75, 72, and this has added
Another 72.
Consistent delivery.
Consistently impressing the judges.
Tonya couch by contrast started well and has faded just a little bit.
A 3.2 degree of difficulty.
It's Tonya's time with the arm stand with her gymnastic background.
There should be a cinch.
good arm strength to push off that's where the extra strength comes in to buy you the time to approach and the toes together 72 solid 7.5 7.5 7.5
Philly on stand with the arm stand.
Thank you very much.
Different technique on the arm stand and the push came from much higher.
She wasn't pushing away off the board, she was pushing up off the board.
Tightly into the bike.
In quest as ever, 69.3, the score for a 267.
So Pandalela, she's had a good series of dives so far.
Now she's got an inward three and a half somersault, 3.2 degree of difficulty.
Currently second, needs to keep the focus.
21 year old from Sarawak on East Malaysia.
A 3.2 degree of difficulty.
Inwards three and a half somersaults with Tuck.
Toes were together, but... We've seen tighter tucks from Pandalela.
Not the cleanest entries.
At this level of competition, the slightest error is really exaggerated.
68.8 for the score for Pandalela.
Will that be good enough to keep her in second place?
And it is for the moment.
Megan Benfito.
The arm stand with the triple somersault.
The big splash at the end is a bit of a giveaway.
It's not a bad dive, it's just that the execution and the entry will be penalized.
It's not a bad dive at all in terms of athleticism, but just gone over the top a little bit on the entry.
That will cost her points from the judges.
The harshest of critics.
The score is 59.4.
A 3.3 degree difficulty for the current leader.
She's done nothing to suggest that she won't be in the box seat come round five.
A 3.3 degree of difficulty and she's quickly into the tuck.
Again, it's the time of the Chinese athletes when they come out of the somersaults.
79.2.
By her standards, an ordinary dive, but by international standards, top draw, top draw.
She still leads the way, there's Yuhi Xia.
Mandelela still holds on, in fact, added to her lead in second place.
Orozco holds onto third, and Tonya Couch has got some work to do.
1.6 points to make up on this final round of dives.
Just comparing like with like there.
Shot on the left had the leader Huixia.
How tight she is into the tuck, how smooth she was out into the final entry.
Fifth round.
The backward three and a half somersault for Alejandra Orozco.
This is her toughest dive for the competition.
Currently in third.
What a result this will be if she can maintain it.
Oh, entry into the water is poor.
Should be marked down for that.
He certainly had the elevation at the approach.
She's being marked right down.
Just couldn't get out of the somersaults and.
That's a disappointing end.
It's just a 34.7.
Put it down to experience.
Top competitions all about you've got no margin for error.
It's on your couch She's got a chance now a podium place is hers for the taking Nicely delivered the reverse two-and-a-half somersault with tuck and
And it was a graceful effort.
The degree of difficulty is only 2.8.
That means the execution has got to be well nigh perfect.
And it's a solid total.
Low to mid 70s will suffice.
It's so much time and a very graceful effort from the 24 year old from Plymouth.
And nine and two 8.5s count, 72.8.
That's an excellent conclusion.
And a probable podium place for Tonya Couch.
Two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists.
A degree of difficulty of 3.2 for Roslyn Fillon.
Really nicely executed.
Depth of twists.
Opened operational and the dive is halfway done.
Next it just takes off.
75.2.
That's her best dive by some margin for Roslyn Filion.
Now Pandalela Rinong.
Backward two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists, as we've just seen.
Degree of difficulty 3.2, currently second.
Very consistent performer, Pandalela Rinong.
Beautiful entry.
All those hours in the gym, in the pool, working hard, strategizing, perfecting.
It makes it worthwhile when you're producing performances, which is a definite podium, probably second for Pandalela.
That's an excellent performance from Pandalela Rinong.
Confident, straight legs, toes together, clean as a whistle.
76.8, it deserves the smile.
368.5, she knows.
She's thrilled to bits.
Same dive for Megan Benfato, the Canadian.
Again, really nicely executed, arguably the best dive of the tournament.
And I think statistically we'll say it's the best dive of the tournament.
Almost inseparable from what we just saw from Pandalela Rinong, and was waxing lyrical about that.
The Quebec native has done well there.
Moves into 4th place.
Roscoe's disastrous final round will drop her to the bottom of the pile.
That's better, says the coach.
So this to crown a Queen.
A very satisfying sound as she enters the water, barely a ripple.
And as the scores are read out,
It equals the best performance of this particular competition, an 86.4 from Lu Hexia.
The outstanding diver.
The Chinese, as is so often the case, was setting the standards for the others to follow.
And now she's just climbing out of the shadows of General Lin.
Confirmation.
Bronze for Tonya Couch from Great Britain.
Pandalela Rinong from Malaysia picks up the silver.
Yuhui Xia picking up as expected the gold.
The Canadians fourth and fifth.
The teenager Orozco.
She had a good competition up until the final dive, which you've got to execute.
And I think she's executed a pretty solid dive.
Toes nicely together at the finale.
That's always a good indication.
And a 75.2 for a total of 142.7 is a good effort by the girl from Guadalajara.
It's on your couch from Great Britain.
Inward three and a half somersault.
3.2 degree of difficulty.
Lovely strong stance on tiptoes.
And a good execution.
She's got a gymnastic background, has Tonya.
Quickly into the pike.
Perhaps didn't just spot her entry into the water perfectly.
It's solid though.
70.4 to 7.5 and a seven counting.
Overall 145.6.
Coaches are poolside.
Instant feedback from just about every dive.
Filion.
Backward, three and a half somersault.
Degree of difficulty, her highest so far, 3.3.
26 year old native of Quebec.
It's a little bit rushed as she's just trying to get out of the.
Back some assault.
Makes them comfortably.
Toes pointed.
69.3.
Full stretch is the coaching tip.
As Pandelela prepares.
Backwards two and a half somersaults in the pike position.
Currently second after the first round.
That's very nicely delivered.
Good aggressive movement into the pike.
Not early, arched back just a little bit over.
giving a bigger splash than it probably deserved.
It's a 69.68 across the board.
146.1.
So she'll be at the very least in the top three.
What depends on the dive executed by Megan Benfato.
She took a long time to settle.
Inward three and a half somersaults in the tuck position.
She needs 72.6 to leapfrog Pandalela.
She really, really elevates her.
This will be an inward two and a half somersault from Pike.
Spotted that very nicely.
It's a 2.8 degree of difficulty.
So the execution has got to be just about perfect to pick up good points.
Anything approaching the high 60s, 70s is a job very well done.
She won't be far off that.
Nice tight pike, early release.
Toes pointed, overshoots the entry.
2.8s and a 7.5.
Then stretch, 198.10 is the total.
With a 65.8 score by the judges.
Now Pandelela from the arm stand.
This will be a back double somersault.
They have to go through each of the disciplines throughout their five dives.
Little push off on the arms, absolutely essential.
It's a good, strong arm stand.
And I think she's scored highly on that one.
The twist is strong, the toes are pointed and perfectly together.
It's always the last little clue.
That's the important element, the little push, just as you're falling.
Nice, clean entry on Panda Lele.
is rewarded with a 76.8.
It's approaching the very good category.
Ben Faito was a genuine contender after the first two rounds and slipped away a little bit.
A 3.3 degree of difficulty.
Wasn't the perfect entry.
Back with three and a half somersaults in the tuck.
Did she get out of the tuck in time?
There's plenty of spring into the tuck, but coming out of it, she's
There's a big splash there.
The entry is such an important element.
Just unable to flick the legs forward.
10 meters is a long way up, but as soon as you're in the air, it disappears very quickly.
A 57.8.
Clear leader.
This is the arm stand.
Followed by a backwards double somersault.
Lovely.
Great form and great strength on the arm stand, perfectly perpendicular.
Then a little push away to give her the time to perform this somersault element in the execution.
And an excellent clean entry.
High marks almost guaranteed for that.
Again, that's the element, and she just buys herself
Extra time, almost too much extra time.
Yuhi Xia, three nines count and 86.4.
It's her best dive of the competition.
It's the best dive of the competition so far.
18 dives so far, 12 still to go.
Two each for each of the competitors still.
Pandelela holding on to second place.
In fact, she's strengthened that.
And Orozco, the young Mexican, has leapfrogs on your couch into the podium positions.
To this whole competition.
This is the first of the new series of the Diving World Series.
to do so here.
Can Pandalela or Megan really upset them?
Tonya Couch is capable of some high-quality diving.
But it's the 16-year-old Alejandro Orozco who'll get us underway.
She participates in the 2012 Olympics in the synchronized 10-meter platform.
Now she's going solo and she'll start us off
Here's the judges, seven judges.
The best two scores and the worst two scores will be taken out of the reckoning.
The three in the middle multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
will determine the score for each particular dive in the women's event.
There are five dives, each has been predetermined.
And the degree of difficulty is known in advance.
Coaches getting ready.
There's Pandalela's coach.
So the Guadalajara born at Roscoe for Mexico will get us underway.
women's 10 meter platform.
7th of 8th events at this diving World Series event in Beijing.
Athletes then have to think of.
Getting the passport stamped and moving on to the United Arab Emirates because Dubai is next week, but firstly focus.
On this.
This will be a forward three and a half somersault in the pike position.
Degree of difficulty, three.
Nicely delivered from Alejandro.
Getting the first dive out of the way, so important.
You're looking for
Low 70s mid 70s.
If you're down.
Diving first to get yourself up and running.
And the Roscoe that's nicely executed.
So as we're together, which is always a good indication, solid score, solid start of 67.5 for a Roscoe.
This is 24 year old Tonya Couch, hails from Plymouth in the southwest of England, arriving from Great Britain.
It's a backward two and a half somersault with one and a half twists.
Nice clean entry from Tonya.
A 3.2 degree of difficulty to get her five dives up and running.
Again, anything around mid-70s is a solid start.
Chinese divers will be looking for the mid-80s, but anything mid-70s, it's just about right.
Toes nicely pointed.
Entry good.
And a 75.2 score.
Two eights and a 7.5.
The judges scores the count multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
First of the two Canadians.
This is Rosalind Filion.
Tiny diver.
Bundle of energy.
Forward three and a half somersault.
Nice, confident approach.
And the coaches are happy.
They think she's nailed it.
A bronze at the 2012 Summer Olympics in the Synchro event.
Spotting the entry.
She's picked up 63 points.
It did take a long time to set herself before getting into that tuck.
And the entry.
Not exactly perpendicular, so Megan has 64 for 137.5.
The danger is she might drop from second to fifth, such as the tightness of competition in this women's final.
This is the clear leader from the first round.
An inward three and a half somersault in tuck.
Lovely spring.
Yeah, just that little bit of extra height.
Tight somersaults.
Nice tight tuck.
Always seems to have so much time and barely a ripple on entry into the pool.
That's a 78.4.
And top ranked again in 8.5.
It was a nine.
Marked by one of the judges as the highest.
And the 7.5 chalked off.
So after two rounds.
Xu Xia leads 14.8 points clear of Pandalela Rinong, who is just 0.5 clear of Tonya Couch.
That's a good battle.
Any one of second to sixth could be in the podium at the end of five rounds.
But good start from Pandalela.
Tonya, very competitive but outstanding from the Chinese athlete Liu Xu Xia.
We are at the WaterCube, the venue for the Diving World Series 2014, the first competition of the season here in Beijing.
It's the eighth season of the FINA Diving World Series, sponsored this year by NVC Lighting.
Mexican fans everywhere.
Alejandro Roscoe.
Great experience for the 16 year old.
A 3.2 degree of difficulty for that inward three and a half somersault.
The youngest ever athlete to represent Mexico at the 2012 Olympics.
It's a very solid dive.
Recognized by the judges little peek at the scoreboard 72.
37.5, the scores the count from the judges.
Little nod of approval from her coaches on the poolside.
Tonya Couch from Plymouth.
Forward three and a half somersault.
Good confidence approach.
Nice spring into the dive.
Just gets that little bit of extra air.
What's the execution like in the air?
The marking is a 67.5.
She doesn't bring nods of approval from Tonya.
I think she thought she was a little bit better than that.
Goes to the coaches.
Filion currently ranked sixth, but a good dive here, which is possibly a little bit less than I think the coaches reckon she deserved.
Three sevens the scores that count.
Instant feedback from all the coaches.
Alright, Malaysia's Pandalela Rinong.
Bronze medalist at the 2012 Olympics in this competition.
Forward three and a half somersault in the pike position.
The agree of difficulty 3.0.
Again, a lovely clean entry into the water from Pandalela.
She's still only 21 years of age, comes from East Malaysia, Sarawak.
There's much of her training up here in Beijing.
She's picked up a 76.5 opening round score.
That's a very solid start from Pandalela.
Megan Benfaito, she's up next.
The first of her five dives will be a forward three and a half somersault.
Dive 107B as they call it.
Same as we've just seen from Pandalela.
25 year old who hails from Montreal in Canada.
Again, there's good reaction from her coaches.
She won her qualifying group earlier on this morning.
It is always good for confidence.
Nice tight pike.
Spots the entry.
Toes nice and close together.
73.5 and 8.5 and two eights.
The scores, the counting.
Eight, the lowest any of the seven judges awarded at.
Now then, the favorite, Lujica.
The dive of choice, the forward three and a half somersault in Pike.
Rapturous applause.
She's rather overshadowed by Chen Ruolin is Lihui Xia.
She won one of these tournaments in last year's World Series event.
She's got off to a cracking start here.
Nice tight pike.
Confident approach.
Straight legs.
Out early into the dive and a perfect entry.
82.5 is the unofficial scoring card.
The official confirmation comes now indeed 82.5 and 9.5 and two nines.
Anything 9.5 is perceived to be excellent.
And that's a first round lead as expected for you.
He's here.
And the leather inong from Malaysia.
Currently in second place, 1.3 points ahead of Britain's Tonya couch.
With Megan Bonifeto a further 1.7.
Down in fourth place.
Good start.
Back to Alejandro Orozco.
She'll start this time with an arm stand.
And then we'll release into a back double somersault.
Really have difficulty 3.2.
Looking for the approach, you're looking for how solid the arm stand is.
Athletic agility and strength required at the top of the dive.